# TAOUFIK A.

(984)228-0354 | toufikaminew@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/taoufika | GitHub: https://github.com/lbladma | Portfolio: https://lbladma.github.io/My Portfolio

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer and an aspiring CyberSecurity professional with a Computer Science BA degree, over 8 years experience working in IT as a senior computer engineer, system admin by day, and web designer by night which helped me accumulate a couple of years experience working as a freelancer web designer. Currently transferring my extensive IT experience and knowledge towards specializing in Software Development and Cyber Security.

### CODING SKILLS

- Web Development Languages [HTML5, CSS3, & JavaScript]
- Version Control [Git, GitLab]
- Databases [MongoDB, MySQL]
- Frameworks and Libraries [jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js]
- Runtime Environment [Node.js]
- Deployment [Github, Heroku]
- Quality Assurance [Jest]
- Computer Science [Big O Notation, Database Theory]
- Server Side Development [User Authentication, Progressive Web Applications (PWAs)
- MERN Stack [MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js]
- API Interaction [API, JSON, AJAX]

### OTHER SKILLS

Team Player. Communication, Problem Solving, System administration, Trouble-shooting, Active directory, Domain/Local users/groups/computers management, Windows Firewall, Windows Security, Windows Defender, Symantec EndPoint Security, Antivirus Scanning, Desk, Desktop/Technical Support, Service Desk, Customer Satisfaction, Application/Server/Network Monitoring, Problem-Solving, Hardware/Software, Administration/Installation, EPIC healthcare Software support. Medical and hospital systems. Hospital pagers. Customer Service, Billing Support. Project implementation, Devices Setup, Mac, Linux commands, cmd, PowerShell, Linux/Windows hardening. POS, Aloha, MenuLink, Taleo, SCCM. CFC, NCR, Radiant, KDS, NBO. ServiceNow. HP manager. CRM. Zendesk. LAN/WAN/WAP. Routing/Switching. Network protocols.

#### CODING PROJECTS

#### • GROUP PROJECTS

#### VodU | https://github.com/lbladma/Final-Project | https://vodu2.herokuapp.com

- Project Summary:
  - A community where gamers can interact with each other in the form of comments with upvotes and downvotes, watch videos of other users' game play and provide critiques, and post videos of their own content for feedback and advice from other users.
- Core responsibilities in project:
  - Frontend, CSS, styling, Debugging, Testing.
  - Project meetings, Documentation, ReadMe and presentation
- Tools / languages used
  - JavaScript, HTML/CSS
  - NoSQL, Express.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Node.js React.js
  - SQL Server, MySQL, API, JSON, AJAX
  - Visual Code Studio, GitHub, Heroku

# Rehab-Connect | https://github.com/lbladma/Rehab-Connect | https://vodu2.herokuapp.com

- Project Summary:
  - This is a social website meant for former addicts to connect with others and build relationships in the hope of
    overcoming the day to day challenges that come with recently coming out of rehab. This is achieved through
    posting to certain milestones on the site and viewing others stories as they have reached that milestone as
    well.
- Core responsibilities in project:
  - Frontend, CSS, styling, Debugging, Testing.
  - Project meetings, Documentation, ReadMe and presentation
- Tools / languages used
  - JavaScript, HTML/CSS
  - NoSQL, Express.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Node.js React.js
  - SQL Server, MySQL, API, JSON, AJAX
  - Visual Code Studio, GitHub, Heroku

# I'm Feeling | https://github.com/lbladma/Project1-Interactive-Web-APP | https://lbladma.github.io/Project1-Interactive-Web-APP/

- Project Summary:
  - This app is built to allow users to search for places relevant to their mood/feeling.
  - This app solves a real-world problem for anyone in need to socialize by visiting a place that matches their mood/feeling.
- Core responsibilities in project:
  - Weekly Project Meeting Management,
  - Demo, Testing, Debugging
  - Materialize, CSS, Styling and Frontend
- Tools / languages used
  - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Materialize.
  - NoSQL, Express.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Node.js React.js
  - SQL Server, MySQL, API, JSON, AJAX
  - Visual Code Studio, GitHub, Heroku

#### • INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS:

#### Password\_Generator | https://github.com/lbladma/Password\_Generator\_Project

I https://lbladma.github.io/Password Generator Project/

- Project Summary:
  - The objective of this project is to allow users to generate a strong password based on specific requirements selected by the user. below are the detailed Project requirements and criteria.
- Tools / languages used
  - HTML, CSS, JavaScript
  - Visual Code Studio, GitHub.

# Weather APP | https://github.com/lbladma/Weather-Dashboard-App | https://lbladma.github.io/Weather-Dashboard-App/

- Project Summary:
  - This project's main purpose is to build a weather dashboard app that will run in the browser and feature dynamically updated HTML and CSS.
  - This Project uses the OpenWeather One Call API https://openweathermap.org/api/one-call-api to retrieve weather data for cities which is done by making requests with specific parameters.
- Tools / languages used
  - JavaScript, HTML/CSS
  - LocalStorage, React.js
  - Visual Code Studio, GitHub

# Javascript Quiz | https://github.com/lbladma/JS\_Quiz\_Project | https://lbladma.github.io/JS\_Quiz\_Project/

- Project Summary:
  - The main purpose of this project app is to allow me to showcase my learned skills using Javascript, Bootstrap, CSS, and HTML.
  - This project is a multi-choice questions coding quiz.
  - The project's app runs in the browser and features dynamically updated HTML and CSS powered by the written JavaScript code, which has a polished, clean, and responsive user interface
- Tools / languages used
  - JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap.
  - Visual Code Studio, GitHub, Heroku

# Work Day Planner | <a href="https://github.com/lbladma/Work-Day-Planner-App">https://github.com/lbladma/Work-Day-Planner-App</a> | <a href="https://lbladma.github.io/Work-Day-Planner-App/">https://lbladma.github.io/Work-Day-Planner-App/</a>

- Project Summary:
  - The main purpose of this project app is creating a simple calendar application that allows a user to save events for each hour of the day by modifying starter code.
  - This app will run in the browser and feature dynamically updated HTML and CSS powered by jQuery.
- Tools / languages used
  - JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap.
  - jQuery, LocalStorage, Moment.is.
  - Visual Code Studio, GitHub, Heroku

FOR MORE PROJECTS, PLEASE VISIT <a href="https://lbladma.github.io/My\_Portfolio/MyProjects.html">https://lbladma.github.io/My\_Portfolio/MyProjects.html</a>

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Senior Information Technology Specialist

2020 - Present

#### **HCL Technologies**

Raleigh, NC

- Coordinated and managed relationships with vendors and support staff that provide hardware / software / network problem resolution.
- Use the Incident Management System to document and manage problems and work requests and their respective resolutions and circumventions.
- Answered telephone calls, email, instant messages, and assigned tickets from users; Assign work orders / incidents
  to appropriate support teams and follow up until closure which helped 90% of backlog tickets, and meet 95% SLA
  metrics.
- Participated in on-going training and departmental development which allowed the team to stay updated with policies and new procedures.

#### Taleo HealthStream Tier II Remote Support Specialist

2019 - 2020

**Tenet Healthcare** 

Dallas, TX

- Provided in person and phone support to internal employees in regards to Taleo software and other HR applications.
- Worked with employees to troubleshoot, diagnose, and resolve system access and functionality issues.
- Provided one-on-one system coaching/training as necessary.
- Assisted the team in running reports and capturing metrics and complete 95% of related projects zon time and as requested
- Daily tasks included but not limited to answering calls. Responding to emails. And reviewing tickets logs and handling requests in a timely manner.
- Reported to team leads or manager with system issues outages and updates.

## Level 2 Support Technician

2018 - 2019

**NEC Corporation** 

Irving, TX

- Provided technical assistance to corporate customers, vendors, service providers with the following: critical system failure, hardware or software issues, general questions, clarification on operational procedures, or require one-on-one training for specific functions with their personal computer.
- Developed or assisted in development of documentation and standard operating procedures and customer service guidelines relating to IT support of Retail Solutions support systems.
- Worked with team members and management to ensure technical issues are handled and escalated.

### Tier III Restaurant Support Analyst

2018 - 2019

Pei Wei

Irving, TX

- Supported in-house developed and third party applications such Aloha Mobile, NCR, Radiant, KDS QSR Auto, Command Center, CFC, MenuLink, Taleo, OLO, and multiple restaurant systems applications.
- Used CCM.VNC.RDP to remote into restaurant File servers and terminals to troubleshoot any issues.
- Scheduled and followed-up of service with vendors; provide hardware, network, and peripheral device installation and troubleshooting.

# **Client Support Professional**

2017 - 2018

#### **Brinker International**

Dallas, TX

- Supported in-house developed and third applications such Aloha Mobile, NCR, Radiant, KDS QSR Auto, Command Center, CFC, MenuLink, Taleo,
- Used Windows Server 2003/2008 for AD related issues including but not limited to users/groups access rights/permission.
- Worked with vendors to provide hardware, network, and peripheral device installation and troubleshooting.

# Cloud Client Support Professional

2016 - 2017

#### **D&H Financial Technologies**

Irving, TX

- Worked cohesively with regional teams and other groups to ensure client services and projects are deployed to plan.
- Used PowerShell to perform multiple admin tasks, manage registry, and access event logs.
- Used C3 cloud platform to access clients cloud portal. Troubleshoot any C3 log in or access issues.
- Supported XenApp and used it to access clients' servers and virtual machines.

Onsite IT Technician 2016

JWDanforth Buffalo, NY

 Deployed and managed multiple projects in place and ensured the completion by the due date and planned future projects.

- Provided one on one, phone, and email support to troubleshoot users' technical problems, concerns and answer any technical questions
- Configured and tested new assigned devices for users such as iPhones, iPads, Laptops, Surface Pros and worked the team to deploy all devices.
- Used VMware/SCCM to remote into servers and VPCs to troubleshoot any issues.
- Used Windows Server 2003/2008 for AD related issues including but not limited to users/groups access rights/permission.

### **Epic Software Support**

2015-2016

#### Children's Hospital of Buffalo

Buffalo, NY

- Answered calls and responded to users' emails in regards to EPIC or any health system application.
- Provided technical support to the hospital's staff including but not limited to doctors and nurses.
- Helped users upgrade to the latest version of EPIC software system.
- Route any non-related EPIC questions or concerns to the correct department or group.
- Conducted follow up calls to users to ensure resolution and software full functionality.

#### Tier II Desktop Support

2012-2015

Earthlink Business Buffalo, NY

- Performed application installation and Win7 compatibility testing, task sequence troubleshooting.
- Communicated with the Level 1 Service Desk resources to document solutions to address common problems.
- Performed reimaging/upgrade desktops and laptops using Inline or PXE boot.
- Diagnosed and resolved technical hardware and software issues.
- Accurately documented, tracked, and monitored problems to ensure a timely resolution.

### **EDUCATION**

**Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate: UNC**, Chapel Hill, NC 05/21-11/21 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor's of Information Technology: Franklin University, Columbus, Ohio

### **Currently pursuing:**

<u>Cybersecurity certificate and CompTia security + Thru Springboard Bootcamp</u>

11/22-06/22